<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ian's Cycling Blog.</title><link>http://cycling.ianbarton.net/</link><description>Cycling Web Pages</description><atom:link href="http://cycling.ianbarton.net/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2018 &lt;a href="mailto:ian@ianbarton.net"&gt;Ian Barton&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 14:28:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>A Loop Through the Cambrian Mountains.</title><link>http://cycling.ianbarton.net/posts/a-loop-through-the-cambrian-mountains/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div class="html"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;lt;iframe src="//rwgps-embeds.com/trips/11614917/embed?privacy&lt;sub&gt;code&lt;/sub&gt;=hRrxHOGaaeUJUAVa" height="500px" width="100%" frameborder="0"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
To view the full route and download a gpx file click &lt;a href="https://rwgps-embeds.com/routes/17716473"&gt;View full route&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The ride is a series of two loops starting at Rhayader visiting
Llanidloes and Caersws. You can just ride the first part of the loop
as far as Llanidloes, ride the whole loop to Caersws, or start in
Llanidloes and do the loop to Caersws.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There is a lot of climbing, around 4,400ft over 45 miles if you do the
whole route. It's probably worth spending the entire day cycling , so
you can enjoy the views and stop for a good look around
Llanidloes. The route is based around Sustrans Route 81 from
Llanidloes to Caerwys, but uses two B roads to avoid following Route 81
both ways. Note that although Route 81 follows the valley alongside
the A470 it winds it way up and down several spurs, so there is much
more climbing than you might think! Route 81 is generally very well
signposted, so easy to follow. However, be aware that at a couple of
points in the ride there are branches of Route 8 and 818 that go off
to the West. Make sure you follow the correct branch, or you might end
up in Aberystwyth!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If you start at Rhayader there is a pay and display car park just by
the turn off for the B4518. Turn right out of the car park and the
climbing starts immediately. Follow the road through Harmon and Pant y
dwr ignoring any turnings to the left and right. After several ups and
downs you go past a big landfill site and there is a long steep
descent into Llanidloes.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Turn right towards the town and then left to cross the bridge over the
river. After a short distance turn right up the B4569 (signposted
Trefeglwys). There is a steep climb up through the woods, leading onto
a ridge with excellent views. There are several ups and downs before a
final long descent to Trefeglwys. There are now fewer hills and a nice
undulating ride into Caersws, where there are local shops.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Note that the turn off to route 81 back to Llanidloes goes off to the
right just before you cross a small stream a few hundred yards before
reaching the village. There is a sign, but it is easily missed when
travelling from this direction. The route back to Llanidloes follows single track
roads, which run parallel to the A470 in the valley below. The route
climbs up and descends several steep spurs before reaching
Llanidloes. There are several restaurants and cafes, but I visited The
Great Oak, which serves vegetarian food and epic slices of cake.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Once in the town you need to turn right next to the Market Hall down a
narrow street (Shortbridge Street, well signposted). At the end of the
street turn left (signposted). After a short distance Route 8 splits
into two branches, make sure that you take the left hand one.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The route continues with several steep climbs to Llangurig, where you
emerge onto the A44 at a T junction. Turn left (signposted Rhayadar)
and then after a few yards take the road to the right
(signposted). Navigation is now straightforward. Just stay on the
single track road until a long descent takes you to a T junction.
Turn left and you will soon be back in Rhayadar.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>routes</category><guid>http://cycling.ianbarton.net/posts/a-loop-through-the-cambrian-mountains/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 16:00:23 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>